Mohamed Tabrez Saqib Ubaidur Rahman, M.Eng.

WEB DEVELOPER ◆ PROACTIVE DESIGNER

796-B Hanson St, Fredericton, NB E3B 4A4, +1-(506)-238-9059. mohamedsaqib1996@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/mohamed-tabrez

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An enthusiastic web developer with a passion for crafting and managing engaging and user-friendly websites with 4+ years of experience in software development. Track record of establishing a good rapport with my teams with zero escalation and completing every task with high quality and efficiency.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, JSON, React.js, Next.js, Redux, Python, PL/SQL, PHP

Development Tools: Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, Vivado Design Suite, Lattice Diamond, Postman, WordPress

Version Control & Build Tools: Git, Maven, Nexus

Integration & Automation Tools: Kubernetes, Jenkins, Terraform, Ansible

Cloud Services: AWS, Azure

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Jun 2023 – Present

Fredericton Botanical Garden Association, Fredericton

- Generating and hosting a responsive user interface to display the plants of New Brunswick for the Fredericton Botanical Garden Association online hosted on Bluehost.
- Effectively addressing multiple problems, designing graphic elements, and updating the database structure during the development cycle.
- Proficiently communicating with the Botanists and Board on the project's progress and hindrances and executing the requirements on React.js, Next.js, JSON, WordPress, AWS, and various DevOps tools.
- Skillfully coordinating with team members of various modules for enhancing functionality and building UI mockups and prototypes for better understanding and easier functionality.
- Acquiring further knowledge of WordPress, Next.js, AWS, and RESTful APIs.

Application Development Analyst

Aug 2018 - Aug 2021

Accenture, Chennai, India

- Modified and managed hospital scheduling/billing tools using Cadence.
- Assisted in designing logical games for a mental health scan app using React.js.
- Developed, automated, and maintained Budget Reports using PL/SQL and BI Publisher in an agile environment.
- Worked on 3 projects and contributed innovative ideas to their ongoing international innovative projects every year.
- Upskilled in languages such as Azure, React, CSS3, Cadence, and PL/SQL.

TRAINING

DevOps June 2023

Git, Maven, Nexus, Kubernetes, Terraform, Docker, Jenkins, and Ansible tools.

AWS Cloud Services May 2023

Computing, Networking, Storage, and Database Services.

EDUCATION

Master of Engineering, Electrical and Computer (3.9/4.3)

Sep 2021 - Dec 2022

University of New Brunswick, Fredericton

Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics, and Communication (8.1/10)

Aug 2014 - Apr 2018

Anna University, Chennai

PROJECTS

NB Plants Website Jun 2023 – Present

Fredericton Botanical Garden Association, Fredericton

- Planning and constructing graphic user interfaces and page navigation elements for the Fredericton Botanical Garden Association using React.js, Next.js, JSON, WordPress, AWS, Jenkins, and Docker.
- Troubleshooting responsive issues and adhering to style and accessibility standards with the aid of the latest Bootstrap and Material UIs.
- Composing and maintaining plant database on WordPress, and AWS.

Regional Voting App

Apr 2024 - May 2024

New Brunswick, Fredericton

- Developed a React.js regional surveying front-end web application to survey the public response to the local plants and vegetation in New Brunswick with a back-end RESTful API.
- Managed and deployed the app on Kubernetes with features such as ConfigMaps, Secrets, Persistent Volumes, Ingress, and Deployment strategies.
- Collected the data by maintaining a PostgreSQL database via Kubernetes Persistent Volumes and Persistent Volume Claims.

Mental Health Scan App

Jun 2020 – Sep 2020

Accenture, Chennai, India

- Programmed responsive and interactive games to detect the mental health status of users in a team of 3 members.
- Operated reusable components and incorporated intuitive UI modules in React.js.
- Integrated API using the Fetch method and automated the app on AWS by administering the automation on Jenkins.

AWARDS

Ace Award May 2021

For building trust, gaining recognition and appreciation within a few months with the new client.

Pinnacle Award Feb 2021

• For being the torchbearer of continuous innovation and agility at scale.

EXTRA-CURRICULARS

Electronics and Communication Department of MSEC

Jun 2016 - Mar 2018

 Served as the President of the department and conducted a national-level technical symposium, conferences, and seminars.

English Literary and Cultural Society of St. Bede's

Jun 2012 – Mar 2014

 Represented my team as the Cultural Secretary and organized various inter-state cultural events and debates.